Hi, this is Sean Hobson, and what we're talking about right now is when is the proper time to use particular passes.
And what we want to talk about right now is the bounce pass.
Bounce passes are very effective.
About the only time you don't want to use a bounce pass is when you're throwing from the top of the key to the perimeter.
Those are long passes.
Any time you're throwing a really long pass, you don't want to use a bounce pass.
It's easy for a defender to come out and steel.
However, if we got these three guys that are running a break, typically you want to use a bounce pass for this reason.
If I'm a defender and I'm trying to defend this fast break, and I come back, if he throws a chest pass here, it's real easy for me to come out and knock that chest pass away.
Give it back to him.
But, if he's coming on the fast break and he throws a good bounce pass to this guy on the fast break, it's really hard to get down while a defender is running back, to get down and defend that bounce pass.
He can catch it low, and go up and score it.
So usually on a fast break, it's much better to use a bounce pass than it is a chest pass, because it's so much harder to defend.
The last one we want to talk about is--let's go ahead and have you post, kick it out.
You come play defense.
And whether this guy plays him on the bottom side or the top side, most of the time it's easier to fake and to throw a good low bounce pass instead of a chest pass, because already he's got his hand in there.
He wants to play this guy in the middle, not on the bottom.
So if Kyle can throw him a low bounce pass to the top, it's much easier for him to work that way off a bounce pass than it is off of a chest pass.
And the same thing if he was fronting him high, we'd have the bounce pass come and wrap around low.
So, the bounce pass is a really good pass to feed the post, and to run the fast break.